Guide to the World War I Pamphlet Collection 1901-1944 (bulk 1914-1919)
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
- Germany - War Relief Effort: Hospitals / Rehabilitation (in German), 1917; Medico-mechanisches Institute der deutschen Kriegs gefangenen fürsorge. Bern: 1917. (book of photographs of German pows in physical therapy) (Box-folder 20/11)
- Germany - War Relief Effort: Prisoners of War (in German), undated; Vertraulich: Anschreiben zum Fragebogen. n.d. (book of guidelines on how prisoners in French prison camps were to be released and relocated to Switzerland); Christlichen Traktgesellschaft. Verzeichnis der fur Kriegsgefangene geeigneten fremdsprachigen Schriften. Kassel, n.d. (No. 11 of a series - title translates as: Directory of the appropriate foreign language rules for prisoners of war); Wie die Franzosen gefangene deutsche Soldaten behandeln! n.d. (Box-folder 20/12)
- Germany - War Relief Effort: Prisoners of War (POWs) (in German), 1915 and undated; [Untitled pamphlet about a musical benefit for German prisoners of war]. n.d.; International Committee of the Red Cross. Berichte über Kriegsgefangenenlager in Deutschland und Frankreich erstattet zuhanden des Internationalen Komitees vom Roten Kreuz in Genf ... Januar bis Juni 1915. Basel: Georg & Cie,1915. (fragile); Vereinbarung zwischen der Deutschen und Französischen Regierung über Kriegsgefangene: 15. Mai 1918 ratifiziert. [s. l.]: [s. n.], 1915. (fragile); Frankfurter Beitung. Sonderabdruck aus Frankfurter Beitung: Die Vermisst. 1915. (extremely fragile); Liste der Franzosischen Gefangenenlager. 1915. (a list of prison camps) (Box-folder 20/13)
- Germany - War Relief Effort: Prisoners of War (POWs) (in German), 1916; Müller, Wilhelm. Bei deutschen Kriegsgefangenen in der Schweiz. Munchen: [s. n.], 1916.; The Red Cross. Vermisst-Kriegs; Gefangen. 1916. (Box-folder 20/14)
- Germany - War Relief Effort: Prisoners of War (POWs) (in German), 1917-1919; Deutsches Rotes Kreuz (Deutschland, Deutsches Reich). Bericht des Bezirksausschusses Gießen für vermißte und kriegsgefangene Deutsche Abteilung des Zweigvereins Gießen vom Roten Kreuz. Gießen: Brühl, 1917. (one pamphlet of a German periodical series, published between 1917-1918); Deutsche Kriegsgefangenen-Fürsorge und Bücherzentrale Bern: Zwei Preisausschreiben. Bern: Deutschen Internierten-Druckerie, 1918.; Ausstellung von Arbeiten der in der Schweiz internierten deutschen Kriegsgefangenen: 14. bis 18. März 1917 im Palmengarten Frankfurt. Frankfurt a. M.: Englert & Schlosser, 1917.; Archiv-Dienst Karl Engelmann. Unsern heimkehrenden Brüdern. Berlin: Arbeitergemeinschaft für staatsbürgerliche und wirtschaftliche Bildung, 1919. (Box-folder 20/15)
- Germany - War Relief Effort: Red Cross (in German), 1916 and undated; Berg, Paul-L., and Edmond Karlemeyer. Sorge für die Hinterbliebenen und Kriegsversorgung. [S.l.]: [s.n.],; Die Arbeitsbehandlung im Reserve-Lazarett Remscheid. Coln: 1916. (Box-folder 21/1)
- Germany - War Relief Effort: Red Cross (in German), 1916; Nagel, C. Die Liebes-Tatigkeit der Schweiz im Weltkriege. Frobenius Basel, 1916. (Box-folder 21/2)
- Germany - War Relief Effort: Religious (in German), 1915-1916; Richter, Julius. Die Mission in dem gegenwärtigen Weltkriege. Berlin: Edwin Runge, 1915.; Zwei Jahre Kriegsarbeit des Vereins vom hl. Borromäus in Bonn a. Rh.: Aug. 1914-Okt. 1916. Bonn: Borromäus-Verein, 1916. (Box-folder 21/3)
- Germany - War Relief Effort: Wounded / Crippled (in German), 1915-1918; Biesalski, Konrad. Die ethische und wirtschaftliche Bedeutung der Kriegskrüppelfürsorge und ihre Organisation im Zusammenhang mit der gesamten Kriegshilfe. Leipzig: Leopold Voss, 1915.; Stoltefuss, Emil. Zur Fürsorge der Kriegsbeschädigten. 1918. (Box-folder 21/4)
- Great Britain - Atrocities Alleged: Against Germany (in English), 1915 and undated; War on the Wounded! London: Joseph Causton & Sons, Ltd., n.d. (2 copies); Morgan, J. H. Germany's Dishonoured Army. [London]: The Parliamentary recruiting committee, 1915.; Great Britain, and James Bryce Bryce. Evidence and Documents Laid Before the Committee on Alleged German Outrages. London: T. Fisher Unwin, Ltd., 1915. (Box-folder 21/5)
- Great Britain - Atrocities Alleged: Against Germany (in English), 1915; Great Britain, and James Bryce Bryce. Report of the Committee on Alleged German Outrages Appointed by His Britannic Majesty's Government and Presided Over by the Right Hon. Viscount Bryce. London: H.M. Stationery Off, 1915. (1 of 2 copies; second copy in following folder) (Box-folder 21/6)
- Great Britain - Atrocities Alleged: Against Germany (in English), 1915; Great Britain, and James Bryce Bryce. Report of the Committee on Alleged German Outrages Appointed by His Britannic Majesty's Government and Presided Over by the Right Hon. Viscount Bryce. London: H.M. Stationery Off, 1915. (second copy) (Box-folder 21/7)
- Great Britain - Atrocities Alleged: Against Germany (in English), 1916; Great Britain. European War. Papers Relating to German Atrocities, and Breaches of the Rules of War, in Africa. London: H.M. Stationery off., Darling and son, limited [printers], 1916. (Box-folder 21/8)
- Great Britain - Atrocities Alleged: Against Germany (in English), 1917; Their Crimes. London: Cassell & Co., Ltd., 1917.; Cook, Theodore Andrea. The Crimes of Germany; Being an Illustrated Synopsis of the Violations of International Law and of Humanity by the Armed Forces of the German Empire. Based on the Official Enquiries of Great Britain, France, Russia and Belgium. With a Preface by Sir Theodore A. Cook. London: The Field & Queen (H. Cox) ltd, 1917. (Box-folder 21/9)
- Great Britain - Atrocities Alleged: Against Turkey (in English), 1917; Toynbee, Arnold J. "The Murderous Tyranny of the Turks". London: Hodder & Stoughton, 1917. (Box-folder 21/10)
- Great Britain - Atrocities Alleged: U-boat Sinkings (in English), 1915-1916 and undated; The Murder of Captain Fryatt. London: Hodder & Stoughton, 1916.; Hurd, Archibald. Murder at Sea. London: T.F. Unwin, 1916.; Milner, Alfred Milner. Cotton Contraband. London: Darling and Son, Limited, 1915.; Murder Again! London, Sir Joseph Causton & Sons, Ltd., (Box-folder 21/11)
- Great Britain - Atrocities Alleged: U-boat Sinkings (in English and Spanish), 1917-1918; Howard, Keble. The Zeebrugge Affair. New York: George H. Doran company, 1918.; Those "Gentlemen" of Germany. S.l: s.n, 1917. (2 copies); La Caballerosidad Alemana. S.l: s.n, 1917. (Box-folder 21/12)
- Great Britain - Celebrations (in English), 1918; The Fourth of July in London. London: Darling & Son, Ltd.,; Hay, Ian. Independence Day in London 1918: Resolutions and Speeches at the Central Hall, Westminster. London: Hodder and Stoughton, 1918. (2 copies) (Box-folder 22/1)
- Great Britain - Domestic Politics: Air Raids (in English), 1918; Paget, Henry Luke. Records of the Raids. London: Society for Promoting Christian Knowledge, 1918.; The Metropolitan Observation Service: 1914-1918. (letters concerning the closing of the Observation Service) (Box-folder 22/2)
- Great Britain - Domestic Politics: Food Shortages (in English), 1914-1919 and undated; Yates, May. There is a World-wide Shortage of Wheat. London: The Bread and Food Reform League, n. d.; War: Makes the Food Question of Momentous Importance. London: The Bread and Food Reform League, 1914.; Yates, May. Science and Daily Bread. London: Jarrold & Sons, 1916. (missing last page of pamphlet); Lloyd George, David. Fact V. Fiction. Mr. Lloyd George's Statement on Shipping and Food Supplies. London: Hodder & Stoughton, 1917.; "Fight the Famine" Council. The Spectre of Famine, No. 6. London: Pelican Press, 1918.; Burall, A.A. Problems of the Famine: Transport in Europe. London: Fight the Famine Concil, 1919. (Box-folder 22/3)
- Great Britain - Domestic Politics: Immigration (in English), 1915; The Case of Naturalised British Subjects. [London]: Sackville, Barton & Co., Ltd., 1915. (Box-folder 22/4)
- Great Britain - Domestic Politics: India (in English), 1915; Vogel, Jean P. A Suspect Manifesto and a Neutral Expert. N.p, 1915. (Box-folder 22/5)
- Great Britain - Domestic Politics: Industry (in English), 1916-1918; Addison, Christopher A. The Manufacture of Munitions. London: J. Truscott & Son, Ltd, 1916.; Plymouth (England). Report on the Reconstruction of Industry, Prepared After a Series of Conferences of Plymouth and Cornwall Citizens Who Were Also Employers and Trade Unionists, Held at Plymouth in March and April, 1918. London: Argus Printing Company, 1918.; Addison, Christopher Addison. British Workshops and the War. London: T.F. Unwin, 1917. (2 copies) (Box-folder 22/6)
- Great Britain - Domestic Politics: Ireland (in English), 1919 and undated; Ireland and International Revolution. Vacher & Sons, Ltd.,; An Imperial Danger. The Sinn Fein Menace. The Irish Problem in a Nutshell. Dublin: Ponsonby & Gibbs, 1919.; The Irish Unionist Alliance. What has Ireland done in the way of Recruiting during the War? Dublin: 1919.; De Valera, Eamonn. The Foundation of the Republic of Ireland in the Vote of the People; Results of the General Election of December, 1918--a National Plebiscite Held Under British Law and British Supervision. 1919. (Box-folder 22/7)
- Great Britain - Domestic Politics: Labor (in Dutch), 1917; Seddon, J A. Waarom De Britsche Arbeiders Den Oorlog Steunen. 's-Gravenhage: Drukkerij en uitgevers-maatschappij "De Hofstad", 1917.; Tillett, Ben. Wie Draagt De Verantwoordelijkheid Voor Den Oorlog En Waarom?'s-Gravenhage: Drukkerij en uitgevers-maatschappij "De Hofstad", 1917. (Box-folder 22/8)
- Great Britain - Domestic Politics: Labor (in English), 1917-1920 and undated; McCurdy, C. A. A Clean Peace: the War Aims of British Labour: Complete Text of the Official War Aims Memorandum of the Inter-Allied Labour and Socialist Conference, Held in London, February 23, 1918. New York: George H. Doran Co, 1918.; MacDonald, J. Ramsay. War and the Workers: A Plea for Democratic Control, No. 8. London: The Union of Democratic Control, n. d.; General Federation of Trade Unions, and J. O'Grady. To the Workmen Affiliated to the Confederation General Du Travail. London: General Federation of Trade Unions, 1917.; Co-partnership after the war: a memorandum submitted febr. 1917, to the Reconstruction Committee appointed by H. M. Government; re-issued, with revised appendix, January 1920. London: Labour Co-partnership Association, 1920. (Box-folder 22/9)
- Great Britain - Domestic Politics: Labor (in Spanish), 1917; Tillett, Ben. La responsabilidad de la guerra y a quienes corresponde esa responsabilidad. Londres: Eyres and Spottiswoode, 1917.; Para la salvaguardia del obrero británico. Londres: [s.n.], 1917. (Box-folder 22/10)
- Great Britain - Domestic Politics: Labor/Workers' National Committee (in English), 1914-1916; Workers National Committee. Report: August, 1914 to March, 1916. London: Co-operative Printing Society, Ltd., 1916.; War Emergency: National Workers' Committee Meeting Minutes. Ed. Workers National Committee. London: Co-operative Printing Society, Ltd., 1914-16. Print. (serial publication) (Box-folder 22/11)
- Great Britain - Domestic Politics: Labor/Workers' National Committee (in English), 1917-1918; War Emergency: National Workers' Committee Meeting Minutes. Ed. Workers National Committee. London: Co-operative Printing Society, Ltd., 1917-18. Print. (serial publication) (Box-folder 22/12)
- Great Britain - Economics & Finance (in Danish), 1918; Zimmern, A. E. Det Okonomiske Vaaben: I Krigen Imod Tyskland. London: Alabaster, Passmore & Sons, Ltd., 1918. (Box-folder 22/13)
- Great Britain - Economics and Finance (in English), 1915 and undated; Leonard, R. M. & The Secret Comissions and Bribery Prevention League, Inc. The Army and Corruption: A Study in Blue Books. London: Bradbury, Agnew, & Co. Ld.,; Greenwood, Arthur. Foreword.; Greenwood, Arthur. Foreword. (this pamphlet is different than the one listed above); Ashby, Arthur W. Foreword.; Fisher, H. A. L. The British Share in the War. London: T. Nelson & Sons, 1915.; Parker, Gilbert. What is the Matter with England? Criticism and a Reply. London: Darling & Son, Ltd., 1915. (2 copies) (Box-folder 22/14)
- Great Britain - Economics and Finance (in English), 1916-1919; The Treaty Position. London: V & S, Ltd., 1916.; Mills, J. Saxon. Britain's Financial Burden. London: Printed by Eyre & Spottiswoode, 1917.; Lloyd George, David. Peace and Retrenchment. The Prime Minister's Call to the Nation. London: Harrison and Sons, 1919. (2 copies) (Box-folder 22/16)
- Great Britain - Economics and Finance: War Debts (in Danish and English), 1916-1918; Revelstoke, John B. British Staying Power: Lord Revelstoke's Views. Anglo-American Sympathies. London: J. Causton & Sons, 1916.; Vose, Edward Neville. Storbritanniens storsindede Handelspolitik. London: Alabaster, Passmore, 1918.; Ret frem eller utenom. [Anon.]. London: Hodder and Stoughton, 1916. (Box-folder 22/17)
- Great Britain - Foreign Politics (in Danish), 1914; University of Oxford. Grundene til Englands deltagelse i krigen. London: Oxford Universitets Bogtrykkeri, 1914. (Box-folder 22/17)
- Great Britain - Foreign Politics (in English), 1916-1917; Smuts, Jan C. War-time Speeches: A Compilation of Public Utterances in Great Britain. New York: George H. Doran, 1917.; Parker, Gilbert. Two Years of War. London: Burrup, Mathieson & Sprague, 1916. (Box-folder 22/18)
- Great Britain - Foreign Politics: Blockades (in English), 1915-1917; Headlam, James Wycliffe. The Starvation of Germany. London: Hodder and Stoughton, 1917. (2 copies); Hume-Williams, W. Ellis. International Law and the Blockade. London: Sir J. Causton & Sons, 1916.; Wise, B. R. The Freedom of the Seas. London: Darling & Sons, ltd, 1915. (2 copies); Zamora (Steamship). The Zamora (Part Cargo Ex). Report of the Argument Before Lord Parker of Waddington... London: Reprinted from the Times law reports by Sir J. Causton, 1916.; Sprigg, Stanhope W. The British Blockade; What It Means, How It Works. London: G.B. Dibblee, 1917.; Great Britain. Statement of the Measures Adopted to Intercept the Sea-Borne Commerce of Germany. London: H.M. Stationery Off., Harrison and Sons, Printers, 1916. (Box-folder 22/19)
- Great Britain - Foreign Politics: Blockades (in Swedish), 1917; Murray, Gilbert. Englands Sjopolitik Ett Ord Om Moral Och Vederhaftighet. Stockholm: H. Lundberg & G. Olzon, 1917.; Higgins, A P. Forsvarsvapnade Handelsfartyg Och U-Batskrig. London: Eyre and Spottiswoode, 1917. (Box-folder 22/20)
- Great Britain - Foreign Politics: Diplomatic Matters (in English), 1914; Grey of Fallodon, Edward Grey. European War. Report of a Speech by the Rt. Hon. Sir Edward Grey (Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs) in the House of Commons on the 3rd August, 1914. H & S, 1914.; Asquith, H. H. European War; Report of a Speech by the Rt. Hon. H.H. Asquith (Prime Minister) in the House of Commons on the 6th August, 1914. 1914.; Asquith, H. H. European War; Report of Speeches by the Rt. Hon. H.H. Asquith (Prime Minister) and the Rt. Hon. A. Bonar Law (Leader of the Opposition) at the Guildhall, London, on the 4th September, 1914. 1914.; Russia. Documents Respecting the Negotiations Preceding the War Published by the Russian Government. Presented to Both Houses of Parliament by Command ... October, 1914. London: H.M.S.O., 1914.; Great Britain. Great Britain and the European Crisis. Correspondence, and Statements in Parliament, Together with an Introductory Narrative of Events. London: H.M. Stationery Off., Harrison, 1914. (Box-folder 23/1)
- Great Britain - Foreign Politics: Diplomatic Matters (in English), 1915; Great Britain, Giovanni Giolitti, and Theobald von Bethmann Hollweg. Collected Diplomatic Documents Relating to the Outbreak of the European War. London: H.M. Stationery Off., Harrison and Sons, printers, 1915. (Box-folder 23/2)
- Great Britain - Foreign Politics: Diplomatic Matters (in English), 1916-1918; Correspondence with the United States Ambassador respecting the Safety of Alien Enemies Repatriated from India on the S.S. "Golconda". London: Harrison & Sons, 1916.; McCurdy, C. A. What about the Secret Treaties? The Truth About the "Secret Treaties". London: W.H. Smith & Son, 1918. (2 copies); McCurdy, C A. The Truth About the "Secret Treaties". London: W.H. Smith & Son, 1918. (Box-folder 23/3)
- Great Britain - Foreign Politics: Religious Diplomacy (in English), 1914; Archbishop of Canterbury, et. al. The European War. Replay to the Appeal of German Theologians. Great Britain: H & S, 1914. (Box-folder 23/4)
- Great Britain - Foreign Politics: Territory Questions (in English), 1917 and undated; Headlam, James W. The Dead Lands of Europe. New York: G.W. Doran, 1917.; Armstrong, George G. Russia's Idea of Peace. Manchester: William Morris Press, 1917.; Brooks, Sydney. The Real Problem of Alsace-Lorraine. The North American Review, n.d. (Box-folder 23/5)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: American-British (in English), 1915 and undated; Parker, Gilbert. The United States and This War, a Word in Season: Speech Delivered to the Pilgrims' Society ... London, on the 15th of April, 1915, on the Occasion of the 50th Anniversary of the Death of Abraham Lincoln. London: Darling, 1915. (2 copies); Dikaios Logos, pseud. An Ordinary Briton's View of the War. An Open Letter to a Senator of the U.S.A. 1915.; Parker, Gilbert. Is England Apathetic?: A Reply. London: Darling, 1915.; What the Allies Are Fighting For (Translation from their reply to President Wilson.). London: Eyre & Spottiswoode, Ltd., (2 copies) (Box-folder 23/6)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: American-British (in English), 1916-1918; Murray, Gilbert. The United States and the War. London: W. Speaight & Sons, 1916.; The Case of the Allies: Being the Replies to President Wilson, and Mr. Balfour's Despatch. London: Hayman, Christy & Lilly, 1917. (2 copies); Lloyd George, David. "Companionship in Arms.". London: Hodder & Stoughton, 1917.; Grey of Fallodon, Edward Grey. The Conflict for Human Liberty. New York: G.H. Doran Co, 1918. (Box-folder 23/7)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: Armenien-British (in English), 1918-1919 and undated; British Armenian Committee. Allies' Debt to Armenians. London: John Procter,; Lord Mayor's Fund. The Plight of Armenian and Assyrian Christians: Report of Public Meeting Organised by the Lord Mayor's Fund, Held at Central Hall, Westminster, on December 4, 1918. London: Spottiswoode, Ballantyne, 1918. (2 copies); Raffi, Aram. The New Armenia; Claims at the Peace Conference, Boundaries of Proposed State. London: Spottiswoode, Ballantyne & Co., Ltd, 1919.; Armenia; Parliamentary debates, House of Lords, Nov. 13, 1918, House of Commons, Oct. 23 ... 1918. The Pelican Press: 1918. (2 copies) (Box-folder 23/8)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: Belgo-British (in English), 1914-1919; Massingham, H. W. Why We Came to Help Belgium. London: Harrison and Sons, 1914.; Seven Million Remained: Our debt of honour to the brave but destitute people who are in Belgium. Spectator. London: Crowther & Goodman, Printers, 1915.; Great Britain. Great Britain and Supplies for Belgian Industries. London ?: s.n, 1916.; The Anti-Slavery & Aborigines Protection Society. Slavery in Europe: A letter to neutral governments from the Anti-Slavery Society. London: Hodder & Stoughton, 1917.; Belgian Protestant Relief Committee. Souvenir of the farewell gathering of the Belgian refugees who have been befriended by the Belgian Protestant Relief Committee, 1914-1918: with a brief account of the work and a few extracts from the letters of appreciation and gratitude printed in English, French, & Flemish. London: Protestant Alliance, 1919. (Box-folder 23/9)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: German-British (in Danish), 1917; Tyske meninger om britisk politik. London: Eyre and Spottiswoode, 1917. (Box-folder 23/10)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: German-British (in Dutch), 1915; Chesterton, G K. Brieven Aan Een Oud-Garibaldiaan. London: Thomas Nelson & Sons, 1915. (Box-folder 23/11)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: German-British (in English), 1914 and undated; The Lichnowsky Revelations. n.d.; Cook, Edward Tyas. How Britain Strove for Peace; A Record of Anglo-German Negotiations, 1898-1914, Told from Authoritative Sources. London: Macmillan, 1914.; Parliamentary Recruiting Committee. "Just for a Scrap of Paper". London: Harrison & Sons, 1914. (Box-folder 23/12)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: German-British (in English), 1915; Gray, Alexander. The Upright Sheaf; Germany's Intentions After the War. London: Methuen & co., ltd, 1915.; Bernhardi, Friedrich von. Bernhardi Converted. A Comparative Study of the Effect of "Drastic Medicine" on the Expressed Opinions of General Von Bernhardi. London: Darling & Son, 1915. (2 copies); "The Scrap of Paper." German Chancellor's Explanation and Great Britain's Reply. 1915. (Box-folder 23/13)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: German-British (in English), 1917-1918; The New German Empire. A Study of German War Aims from German War Sources. London: Hodder & Stoughton, 1917. (2 copies); Lichnowsky, Karl Max. My Mission to London, 1912-1914. New York, N.Y.: George H. Doran Co, 1918. (Box-folder 23/14)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: Italo-British (in English), 1916; Italy Our Ally. London: T. F. Unwin, ltd, 1916. (Box-folder 23/15)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: Polish-British (in English), 1914-1925; The Polish problem: by a Pole. London: Union of Democratic Control, 1914.; Poland under the Germans. London: Sir Joseph Causton & Sons, Ltd., 1916.; Polish Information Committee (London, England). The Resurrection of Poland. Poland for the Poles. London: G. Allen & Unwin, 1916.; Harley, John H. Danzig and the Corridor. London: The National Review, 1925. (Box-folder 24/1)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: Turko-British (in English), 1914; Correspondence Respecting Events Leading to the Rupture of Relations with Turkey. London: H.M. Stationery Off, 1914.; Despatch from his Majesty's Ambassador at Constantinople Summarising Events Leading to the Rupture of Relations with Turkey, and the Reply Thereto. London: H.M. Stationery Off, 1914.; Cook, Edward Tyas. Britain and Turkey: the Causes of the Rupture. London: Macmillan, 1914. (Box-folder 24/2)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: Turko-British (in English), 1917; The Ottoman Domination. London: T. Fisher Unwin, Ltd., 1917. (2 copies); Toynbee, Arnold J. Turkey: A Past and a Future. New York: George H. Doran, 1917. (Box-folder 24/3)
- Great Britain - Foreign Relations: with Neutral Countries (in English & French), 1916-1917; Archer, William. Colour-blind Neutrality: an Open Letter to Doctor George Brandes. London: Hodder & Stoughton, 1916.; Aux Amis De La Paix Et Du Droit International En Suède, En Norvège, Au Danemark Et En Suisse. Londres: Darling & Son, 1916.; Headlam, James Wycliffe. Belgium and Greece. London: Hodder and Stoughton, 1917.; Archer, William. Six of One and Half-a-Dozen of the Other; A Letter to Mr. L. Simons of The Hague. London: T.F. Unwin, 1917. (Box-folder 24/4)
- Great Britain - Military (in English), 1916; The British Empire at War: The men of the empire, their homes and their battlefields. R & L, Ltd., 1916. (Box OS 44)
- Great Britain - Military (in English), 1917; Northcliffe, Alfred Harmsworth. Lord Northcliffe's War Book, With Chapters on America at War. New York: George H. Doran Company, 1917.; Doyle, Arthur Conan. Supremacy of the British Soldier. London: Darling & Son, 1917. (2 copies) (Box-folder 24/5)